mike roberts

🗹 miker@miker.org 🛭 🛇 miker.org 🔏 508.579.4478 🗳 ecopoesis

I am a software leader with two decades experience managing and growing cloud platforms and software as a service products.

I am active proponent of building scalable, well tested, service oriented architectures. I have led the development of numerous platforms over my career, in a variety of languages ranging from the terrible (PHP 5) to the sublime (Scala). I champion moving quickly and smartly. I have taken multiple products from slow, buggy, waterfall to fast, agile, daily releases.

I have run everything from focused, technical tiger teams to entire engineering organizations with dozens of ICs and line managers.

experience

CarGurus

Senior Manager of Algorithmic Traffic Acquisition

My team is responsible for the generation and maintenance of CarGurus' remarketing ads. We also develop CarGurus' recommendation engine and work with marketing to AB test new creative and algorithms. I am also responsible for ATA co-op and fulltime hiring.

Indigo Agriculture

Charlestown, MA 2019 - 2021 Principal Engineer (Manager and Architect) I manage Indigo's back office settlements team. We pioneered high availability, 24/7

uptime services at Indigo. As one of Indigo's architects I introduced reactive patterns and built a widely-used message bus to asynchronously connect our microservices.

Salsify

Principal Engineer (Manager)

Boston, MA 2016 - 2019

Cambridge, MA

2021 - present

At Salsify I led the platform services team, developing the shared infrastructure and code used by Salsify's application teams. Notable accomplishments include building an asynchronous job system and the first wave of Salsify's GraphQL APIs.

TripAdvisor Vacation Rentals

Principal Engineer

Boston, MA 2015 - 2016

Ported legacy FlipKey and Holiday Lettings systems to new unified system.

Leaf Holdings

Software Engineering Manager (Director)

Cambridge, MA 2013 - 2015

I lead both the Android and platform teams, enhancing the existing proof-of-concept to scale to 100k transactions per second. I hired dozens of engineers including a fully remote team in Istanbul. I designed a distributed, eventually consistent data-store cohomed on our Android tablets and on AWS.

Smarter Travel Media

Charlestown, MA 2009 - 2013

Software Engineering Manager (Director and Architect) Built and lead the Tingo team, spinning up a new online travel agency in 9 months. Led hiring across the STM engineering organization. Ran the architectural review board.

education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute

- BS Theatre
- BS Computer Science

skills

expert

- Kotlin
- Scala
- Java
- Rubv
- Python
- GraphQL
- MySQL
- Postgres
- Kafka
- Redis
- Maven
- git
- Terraform

- experienced • Javascript
- PHP
- C# / .NET
- SQL Server
- Kubernetes
- AWS
- Packer
- Puppet
- SBT

faq

Star Trek or Star Wars?

Star Trek

Marvel or DC?

DC

Vim or Emacs?

• Vim

Narnia or Middle Earth?

• Middle Earth

Kanban or Scrum?

• Kanban, but every team is different

Kirk or Picard?

Janeway

Chocolate or vanilla?

• Banana is the superior ice cream